#### Curriculum Vitae

Sachi Sathaye

Psychologist

Contact details

**Phone**: 9561618713

Email: sachi.psychology@gmail.com

Linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/sachi-sathaye/



#### **Profile**

I am a Counselling Psychologist, MSc Clinical Psychology, practicing since February 2024. I employ various compassionate psychotherapeutic practices in a cognitive and psychodynamic framework. Approaching the field of psychology and therapy from an intersectional feminist perspective allows me to understand and address the diverse backgrounds and experiences that shape my clients' lives. I embrace neurodiverse and queer-affirmative approaches based on research and learned experience, to ensure that my practice is inclusive, effective, and affirming. As an advocate for the biopsychosocial model of mental health, I believe in a holistic approach to healing, using supportive psychotherapy and a trauma-informed framework to create healing spaces.

With over 500 hours of clinical internship experience and over 100 hours of experience as a Psychotherapist, under supervision, I have acquired practical skills and insights to support individuals through their unique journeys of growth and healing.

As a psychologist, I aim to promote mental health awareness and make mental healthcare more accessible to the Indian populace while using decolonized, bias-free versions of assessments to provide the most accurate analyses to individuals. Psychoeducation is also a passion of mine for the transformative effect it can have by providing people with basic knowledge about how their minds function and equipping them with the resources to take charge of their lives once more.

#### Education

## **BA** Psychology

Fergusson College | Pune, India | 2019-2022

## **MSc Clinical Psychology**

CHRIST (Deemed to be University) | Bangalore, India | 2022-2024

### Languages

Trilingual proficiency in English, Hindi, and Marathi.

#### Experience

# 1. Supervised online therapy sessions. (February 2024 - ongoing)

- Providing psychotherapeutic services to clients under the supervision of a Clinical Psychologist since.
- Creating treatment plans and interventions for various mental health conditions.
- Empowering clients to take charge of and improve their quality of life.

## 2. Internship at Mind Aid Psychiatric and Counselling Centre. (February 2024 - May 2024)

- Observed Case History intake, MSE assessment, CBT, and REBT sessions.
- Observed cases under the guidance of the psychiatrist and assisted with diagnosis.
- Observed ADHD and Depression assessment.

### 3. Paper presentation. (January, 2024)

- Presented my master's thesis on the Paternal Influences on Disordered Eating at the IAAP Conference at Pondicherry University.
- Explained my thesis about how disordered eating practices can be learned from fathers through observation and paternal interactions of body criticism.

## 4. Internship at Spandana Nursing Home, Bangalore. (August 2023 - October 2023)

- Observed client intake and case history in the OPD.
- Conducted follow-up sessions with OPD clients.
- Attended lectures on various mental health conditions and demonstration of rTMS.
- Interacted with patients in the inpatient ward.

#### 5. Internship at Deenanath Mangeshkar Hospital and Research Centre, Pune. (May, 2023)

- Observed multiple cases with various mental health conditions in the OPD under the guidance of various psychiatrists.
- Observed cases with comorbid psychological and physiological conditions in other medical departments.
- Observed counseling sessions and discussed cases and treatment planning with the psychologist.

# 6. Internship with Beautiful Mind and Soul in Clinical and Counselling Psychology Skills Training. (May, 2022)

- Attended various lectures on Clinical and Counselling skills.
- Training in counselling and soft skills and treatment planning.
- Completed assignments on diagnosis and treatment planning for diverse cases.

# 7. Internship with Beautiful Mind and Soul in Neurological Developmental Disorders Skills Training. (June, 2021)

- Attended various lectures on Neurodevelopmental disorders.
- Training in assessment of multiple treatments and interventions for neurodevelopmental disorders.
- Completed assignments on diagnosis and intervention planning for diverse cases.

## **Professional Development**

- 1. Supervision by a Clinical Psychologist in therapy sessions.
- 2. REBT training workshop, Mind Aid.

- 3. REBT basics workshop, Dr Anjali Joshi.
- 4. Career Coaching Certification, Holistic Coach Academy, Udemy.
- 5. CBT Practitioners Course, The Academy of Modern Applied Psychology.
- 6. Clinical and Counselling Psychology training, BM&S.
- 7. Stress and Anxiety Management, Accredited Course by Elmira Strange, MPhil.

#### **Skills**

#### **Psychotherapy Skills**

- Efficient use of various evidence-based techniques.
- Using techniques from the Cognitive- Behavioural approach for behaviour change.
- Using techniques from the Psychodynamic approach for exploring and treatment of trauma.
- Psychological first-aid and triage.
- Counselling skills, including accurate empathy, rapport building, observation, effective communication, and adaptability.
- Skilled in treatment planning, interventions, and implementation.
- Using Somatic exercises for the management of symptoms such as PMR, breathing exercises, visualization, guided imagery, and self-soothing.

#### **Psychometry and Research**

- Experienced in report writing, qualitative research writing, and effective data analysis.
- Background in qualitative and quantitative research methodologies, and competency in leveraging AI tools for effective content generation.
- Experience in various psychometric assessments such as neurodevelopmental disorder assessments, various mood and anxiety disorder assessments, analysis, and test conduction.